# HARIKA B V

## Software Developer



+91 7729897953

harikabv.developer@gmail.com

PHONE	WEB
EMAIL	GITHUB

www.harikabv.in github.com/Harika-BV

# **PROFILE**

A tech enthusiast with a passion to solve problems and build products. Worked as an Android app developer and UI/UX Designer in budding start-ups. I believe that I am a versatile learner and can get going with any sort of work. Passionate about developing software applications using various tech stack.

#### **EDUCATION**

2017 – 2021 VIT University, Vellore

B. tech in Computer Science and Engineering with Specialization in Bioinformatics

CGPA: 9.41

2015 – 2017 Ratnam Jr. College, Nellore

Class 12<sup>th</sup> (Board of Intermediate Education, Andhra Pradesh)

Score: 988/1000

## EXPERTISE

- MACHINE LEARNING
- ANDROID APP DEV
- WEB DEVELOPMENT
- WEB SCRAPING
- DATA ANALYSIS
- UI DESIGN

### EXPERIENCE

JAN 2021 - JUN 2021
IT ASSOCIATE INTERN - <u>NOVARTIS</u>
Worked as Intern on the projects AISA and DocZ

- Responsible for creating Flask API for one of the useful services and Explored Azure app services for hosting a parsing service
- Performed various experiments on Self supervised learning algorithms for medical images

DEC 2018 - MAY 2020

ANDROID DEVELOPER - <u>ALFALEUS TECHNOLOGY</u>

Worked as Intern on the projects C3FA and IVA

- I was responsible for the product software from ideation stage and did wire-framing, prototyping, feedback iterations and final product delivery.
- My work primarily included development and maintenance of an Android application that can connect to a VR headset wirelessly and perform real time computation and analysis.
- Gained technical skills in algorithm development

## SKILLS

- PYTHON
- JAVA
- DJANGO
- REACT JS
- MySQL

# **SOFT SKILLS**

- TEAM PLAYER
- SELF MANAGEMENT
- LOGICAL THINKING
- CREATIVE
- COMMITMENT

# AWARDS

- Top 30 in HackTheCrisis, a hackathon by Garage48 during Covid-19 pandemic
- Branch topper for academic years 2018-19, 19-20

#### JUN 2020 - SEPT 2020

#### ANDROID DEVELOPER - ASHVA

Worked as Intern on the project FitKnees

- Improved functionality based on field feedback
- Responsible for communicating the app to server using retrofit
- Modifying App Interface for better user experience

#### APR 2020 - JULY 2020

# UI / UX DESIGN INTERN - FINDMIND ANALYTICS

- Understanding the user requirements and converting them into user flows
- Designing wire-frames, visual designs and prototypes
- Designing logo, banners for the company

# **PROJECTS**

#### **CLASSIFYIMAGE**

- Classify Image is a Django web app to classify images into different categories.
- The model is trained on CIFAR 100 dataset using Resnet as base model and using SAM Optimiser.

#### GITHUB PROFILE README CREATOR

- Github's new feature to create a profile-level
   README made me curious to build an automatic
   markdown file creator
- GPRC is a mini-project using React Js. This web app helps to ease the work of creating GitHub profiles.

#### MARK-ED-IT

- Markdown is very useful to write rich formatted content extremely quick
- This web application allows to preview the changes on-the-go you write